jpegreducer.com 2019-01-25

# JPEG Reducer - Cookies and Privacy Policy

_Last updated: 05.10.2018_

JpegReducer belongs to [ID SCOUT SRL](http://jpegreducer.com/), here collectively called the "Company". The Company respects your privacy rights and recognizes the importance of protecting the Personal Information (as defined below) provided by you to us. This Privacy Policy describes how the Company collects, stores, and uses the Personal Information you provide to us through the Company's web sites and through telephone or e-mail communications you may have with us. This Privacy Policy also describes the choices available to you regarding the Company's use of the Personal Information you provide to us, and the actions you can take to access this information and request the correction or deletion of such personal information. 

#### Consent

By using the Company's web sites, you acknowledge that you have read this Privacy Policy and that you consent to the practices described herein with respect to the Company's collection, use and disclosure of the Personal Information provided by you to us. This is the Company's entire and exclusive Privacy Policy and it supersedes any earlier version. We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy in accordance with the terms herein at any time, which is why we encourage you to visit this page often, review this Privacy Policy frequently, and remain informed about any changes to it.   
If, after review, you still have questions about any portion of this Privacy Policy, please contact the Company using the contact information provided at the bottom of this Privacy Policy. 

### General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

The [GDPR law](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=celex%3A32016R0679) is the European law that regulates the [privacy rights of users from the European Economic Area (EEA)](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en). Our Declaration of Conformity can be found here. 

GDPR’s main principle is that users own their personal data, and the companies have the obligation to make the right steps to facilitate the users’ rights: 

  * to know what personal data companies collect, how they store this info and for how long
  * to know if the personal data is shared with third parties
  * to get the personal data (data portability)
  * to delete the personal data
  * to correct the personal data

#### Terms used in this document: We, users, third parties.

  * JpegReducer is the provider of the service, referred sometimes as _we_.
  * By users we understand all the users of our tools and service, and also, the visitors of our site that compresses images through our online image compressor.
  * Visitors are those who browse the web pages of JpegReducer.
  * Customers are the users that purchased paid plans.
  * _Third parties_ are other companies and the services they provide us.

#### 1\. What personal data we collect and how we collect it

From the visitors of our site [http://JpegReducer.com](http://jpegreducer.com/), we collect the following data: IPs, location, browser type, visited pages. 

When images are optimized via our [online compressor](https://jpegreducer.com/), we store them for two hours, together with the optimization details. After that, we delete the images, but we keep the info for 40 days. 

#### 2\. What we do with the collected personal data

##### Customer Support

In order to help our customers we need to use their personal data:

  * Personal data needed for debugging reasons: the domain from where the images are, optimization parameters (file name and size, the time of the optimization).

##### Running the service

For the proper running of our image optimization service we keep: IPs, country of origin, Browser, number of images and PDF files, the names of the images and PDF files, the URLs of the images and PDF files, URIs (domains), PHP version. We need this info to connect our servers to our clients’ servers, where the images needing compression are hosted. The info is also needed for maintenance and for building appropriate tools for our clients. 

##### Information campaigns

We send emails to inform our users about new features, service changes (including Terms and Conditions & Privacy Policy updates), interruptions of our service, possible errors or bugs. These messages are an important part of our communication with our users. 

##### Marketing campaigns

We send newsletters to our users about deals and promotions. Our marketing campaigns could promote other services as well, if we believe that they are compatible with our service, and that they could be useful for our users. We try to keep these types of messages at a maximum of two emails per user/ each month. 

#### 3\. How long do we keep your personal data?

The details of the files processed by our service (names, URLs, optimization parameters, file size, processing date) are stored for 40 days. Each user can access these records from their JpegReducer account, and they can also download a spreadsheet document called an optimization report. 

IPs, email addresses, API keys, and usage data are stored indefinitely. Users have the right to ask us to delete their private data, even if this could mean the termination of the service we provide them due to technical reasons. 

#### 4\. What do we share, with whom, and under what conditions?

Our users’ data is shared with third parties that help us run the service. Please check below a list of the services that have full or partial access to our users’ data, and their privacy and data policies. 

We will tell our users if we intend to share their info with other third parties. We don’t sell personal data. 

#### 5\. Important rights of our users regarding the personal data

_Portability_

: You own your data. Please contact us if you want to receive the information we store about you and about your history with our service. 

_Personal data deletion and account removal_

: Users that want their personal data to be deleted can send a request at 

_help at ShortPixel.com_

, specifying if they want the deletion of all their personal information or just a partial removal. Furthermore, the users can request that their data won’t be handed over or used in some of the ways mentioned in this document. The deletion of personal information can lead to the termination of the service we provide due to technical reasons. 

JpegReducer is powered by ShortPixel technology, so for any contact needs please [contact us there](https://shortpixel.com/contact) if you wish to have your personal data removed. 

_Personal data errors_

: You have the right to correct your personal data. Use our [contact form](https://shortpixel.com/contact) or write us at 

_help at ShortPixel.com_

if you want to correct your data. 

_The right to fill a complaint_

: For us, your personal data is important, and we try to take all the necessary steps to protect your personal data and to respect your rights. You have the right to fill a complaint at the National Authority for the Supervision of Personal Data Processing (Romanian: Autoritatea Naţională de Supraveghere a Prelucrării Datelor cu Caracter Personal), also known as [ANSPDCP](http://www.dataprotection.ro/?page=formulare&lang=ro). 

#### 6\. Third parties that have access to your personal data

##### Zoho - zoho.com

Zoho is an email service provider. Our business emails associated with JpegReducer.com are stored and sent using this service. Zoho can access all the personal data our users share with us via email communication. 

What Zoho does in order to comply with the GDPR law is documented here: <https://www.zoho.eu/gdpr.html>

##### Hetzner - hezner.de

Hetzner is the hosting company from where we rent our servers. Basically, these servers are our service’s engines. They run the image optimization algorithms, compressing the images of our users. 

Hetzner is a German company and it offers a detailed documentation regarding the compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation:  
<https://wiki.hetzner.de/index.php/Datenschutz-FAQ/en>   
<https://www.hetzner.com/news/vertrag-zur-auftragsverarbeitung-gemaess-art-28-ds-gvo-steht-ab-sofort-online-zur-verfuegung-eintrag/?country=mt>

##### Google Analytics - analytics.google.com

We use the Google Analytics service to obtain statistics about our site’s visitor number, origin and behaviour. We took the necessary steps to ensure that the information we gather through Google Analytics is anonymized and that we cannot identify a particular visitor. 

#### Other Information Collected

Some information may be collected automatically every time you visit the Company's web sites, such as cookies and computer information. In addition, information may be collected from other independent, third-party sources. We also collect information about which pages you visit within this site. This site visitation data is identified only by a unique URL. 

#### Cookies

The Company uses both session ID cookies and persistent cookies as part of its interaction with your browser. A cookie is an alphanumeric identifier (a file) that the Company's web sites transfer to your computer's hard drive through a web browser to enable its systems to recognize your browser for record-keeping purposes. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser, while a persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. 

We use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our web sites. We use persistent cookies to identify and track which sections of its web site you most often visit. We also use persistent cookies in areas of its web site where you must register, and where you are able to customize the information you see, so that you don't have to enter your preferences more than once. 

The Company uses Google Analytics, an ad tracking technology that is provided by Google. For more information about Google Analytics, please visit https://www.google.com/analytics/ 

By configuring the options in your browser, you may control how cookies are processed by your system. However, if you decline the use of cookies, you may not be able to use certain features on this site and you may be required to reenter the information necessary complete an order during new or interrupted browser sessions. 

Some of the Company's business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on the site. We have no access to or control over these cookies (see "Third Party Advertising" and "Third Party Cookies" below). Accordingly, this Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by the Company only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. 

#### Log Files

As it is true of most web sites, the Company gathers certain information automatically and stores it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet services provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. The Company uses this information to analyze trends, to screen for fraud, to administer the Company's sites, to track users' movements around the web sites and to gather demographic information about the Company's user base as a whole. 

###### Information from Third Party Sources

To improve services and enhance personalization, the Company may periodically obtain information about you from other independent third party sources and add it to our account information. []()For example, when you visit a site on which the Company advertises, and click through such advertisement, the Company may place cookies on your computer. 

### Use of Information

#### Service-related Announcements

The Company may, but is not obligated, to send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions, when it is necessary to do so. For example, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an e-mail. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications since they are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you may have the option to deactivate your account. 

#### Research

We also collect information for research purposes and to provide anonymous reporting for internal and external clients. The Company uses the information collected for its own internal marketing and demographic studies, to improve customer service and product offerings. 

#### Customer Service

We will communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the products and services you request, and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by e-mail, live chat or telephone, in accordance with your wishes. 

#### Preferences

The Company stores information that it collects through cookies, log files, and third party sources, to create a profile of your preferences, in order to improve the content of the Company's web site for you. 

#### Information Sharing and Disclosure

The Company does not sell or rent any of the information collected to third parties for any purposes, but it shares information with third parties as described below. 

#### Service Providers

The Company discloses the information collected to external service providers, necessary to facilitate the following outsourced operations: address verification, credit card processing, fraud screening and order shipping. 

#### Compliance with Legal Authorities

As required by law, and to enforce customers' or the Company's legal rights, and to comply with local, state, federal and international law, the Company may disclose information to law enforcement agencies. 

#### Choice and Opt-Out

If you no longer wish to receive the Company's promotional communications, you may "opt-out" of receiving them by following the instructions included in each communication. 

#### Links to Other Web Sites

There are several places throughout the Company's web sites that may link you to other web sites that do not operate under this Privacy Policy. When you click through these web sites, this Privacy Policy no longer applies. The Company recommends that you examine the privacy statements for all third party web sites, to understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing your Personal Information. 

#### Storage and Security of Personal Information

The Company stores the information it collects on computers located in a controlled, secure facility, protected from physical or electronic unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. 

#### Security

The Company protects the privacy and integrity of the information it collects by employing appropriate administrative protocols, technical safeguards, and physical security controls, designed to limit access, detect and prevent the unauthorized access, improper disclosure, alteration, or destruction of the information under its control. The Company transmits the information used by its external service providers for the specific outsourced operations listed above, across public and private networks via recognized encryption technologies, such as by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts the information you input. 

Although the Company follows the procedures set forth above to protect the Personal Information submitted to the Company, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Thus, while the Company strives to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, the Company cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

If you have any questions about the Company's security on its web sites, please feel free to contact us using the contact page on the site. 

#### Internet Fraud

The Company has a ZERO TOLERANCE policy for Internet fraud or any attempt to access or acquire customer or other information on its web sites via illegal or surreptitious means. The Company works with local, national, and international fraud investigation agencies and employs a variety of electronic and other means to discourage, detect, and intercept fraudulent activities. The Company aggressively prosecutes, to the fullest extent of the law, those perpetrators apprehended conducting fraudulent activities on its web site. 

The Agencies with which the Company cooperates are: state and local police authorities, the United States Federal Bureau of Investigation, US and International Customs Agencies, and Interpol. 

#### Children

The Company's sites are not intended for or directed to persons under the age of 16. The Company does not buy or sell products or services from or to children. Any person who provides their information to the Company through the Company's web sites attests that they are 16 years of age or older. 

#### Changes to this Statement

The Company will, from time-to-time, update this Privacy Policy, each time revising the last updated date at the top of the Privacy Policy and indicate the nature of the revisions within the statement. The Company will notify customers of material changes to this statement by e-mail or by placing prominent notice on its web site. 

#### Contact Information

You may contact the Company by using the [contact](https://shortpixel.com/contact) form on the site.
